# **Justin Higgins**

linkedin.com/in/higginsjustin github.com/higgins

I am a multidisciplinary engineer with professional experience across the stack. From rapid prototyping to multi-year migrations, I thrive in defining problems, deploying practical solutions and am happy building in green fields or in fields totally overgrown with weeds. Reach out if you'd like to chat!

### **Work Experience**

**Staff Software Engineer** Soundcloud Aug 2023-Present Web team Los Angeles, CA

- Co-designed, built an architecture to hotswap a new web application into a 17 year old one (soundcloud.com) while increasing creator subscription conversions by 22%
- Redesigned/built artist track upload experience, increasing the perceived total time to upload speed
- Improved lighthouse performance scores across high traffic pages LCP: 88%, FCP: 29%, TTB: 13%
- Established engineering processes for tech debt, code review protocols, ADR proposals, testing standards for our international engineering team
- Added Rive animations and leveled up our design team to utilize the new format

**Head of Engineering** Turntable.fm 2021-2023

Core product

Remote

- Launched 4 consumer web and mobile products under my engineering leadership
- Design/built backend services for real-time video streaming, audio messaging and video messaging apps
- Design/built payment and reward service for influencers promoting our services
- Products: Glow.dev, <u>Sup.audio</u>, <u>Seen.lol</u>, <u>Hightide.link</u>

**Staff Software Engineer** Hustle 2017-2021

Web, Mobile, API

San Francisco, CA, USA | Remote

- Doubled perceived performance of client message sending speed
- Designed/built new message "targeting" system allowing clients to reference full history of their platform usage for subsequent use
- Migrated entire codebase off Parse SDK and onto GraphQL gateway

**Founder Selfless** 2015-2020

San Francisco, CA

- Designed/built/launched web and mobile service for sharing physical goods with friends and neighbors
- Solo marketed to communities in the Bay Area

**Senior Software Engineer** 2012-2015 **Apple** 

Beats Music, Core API

San Francisco, CA | Cupertino, CA USA

- Designed/built billing system responsible for subscription revenue through an ancient payment gateway
- Built internal content scheduler for editorial team

#### **Education and Certifications**

**B.A. Physics** University of California, Berkeley.

2007-2011

**B.A. Astrophysics** University of California, Berkeley.

2007-2011

## **Technologies and Languages**

Languages: Typescript, Javascript, Node.js, Python, Elisp, Ruby, Go

Technologies: React, React-Native, GraphQL, Next, MySQL, PostgresQL, AWS, Terraform, Git
Other: Cloudflare, AWS, Drizzle, HonoJS, Rive, Elasticsearch, Redis, Cassandra, Firebase

### **Projects**

- 24HourHomepage.com An internet art project earning ProductHunt's #2 product of the day
- MagicButton.club A passion project promoting indie musicians
- Privatize (git plugin) An open source tool for transparently encrypting HEREDOCs in a git repository
- Everyone Everywhere All At Once An internet art project inspired by the Oscar winning film Everything Everywhere All At Once

#### **Interests**

- I love camping with my wife and dog and exploring Mexico
- I run an annual goals motivation club for people's New Year's resolutions
- I am a film buff and keep a huge collection of DVDs and Blu ray worth owning